Interviewer: This is a choir.
They're called the Oxford Gargoyles.
A gargoyle is a type of statue.
You see them on a lot of old buildings in Oxford and other cities.
Today the Oxford Gargoyles have a rehearsal.
They have a new song to practise,
an old English folk song called Scarborough Fair.
Let’s find out more about the choir and the people in it.
How many people are in the choir?
Freddie: There are thirteen people in the choir.
Interviewer: Are you all students?
Steph: Yes, we’re all students at Oxford University.
Interviewer: What do you study?
Steph: I study music.
Alex: I study music.
Tegan: I study music.
Nell: I study languages, specifically French and Italian.
Interviewer: How often do you practise?
Nell: We practise twice a week – on Wednesdays and Saturdays.
Interviewer: How long do you practise for?
Steph: Each rehearsal is three hours long.
Interviewer: How often do you give concerts?
Tegan: We usually give concerts once a month.
Interviewer: Where do you give concerts?
Nell: We give concerts in lots of different locations.
We give concerts in bars and in theatres and in churches.
Interviewer: What kind of music do you like singing?
Steph: I like singing lots of different types of music, especially jazz and opera.
Interviewer: Do you think everybody can sing?
Freddie: I think everyone can sing because everyone can talk.
Tegan: I think everybody can learn how to sing.
Alex: I think everyone apart from my dad can sing. Yes.
Interviewer: Why do you like singing?
Freddie: I love music
and I love being able to make music with my own body, my own voice,
without needing any extra tools.
Nell: I enjoy singing a lot because I think it’s a really fun thing to do.
And it’s also a very social activity,
so you can do it with anyone, with any of your friends,
and you can do it at any time, or in any place.
Steph: I like singing because I feel happy when I sing.
Interviewer: Do you prefer singing solo or with a group?
Tegan: I definitely prefer singing in a group because I like singing with my friends
and I think it’s really fun to be able to sing together.
Alex: It’s nice to sing solos, but it is more pressure as well.
Steph: I like both solo singing and choir singing.
Choir: Are you going to Scarborough Fair?
Parsley, sage, rosemary and thyme
Remember me to one who lives there
She once was a true love of mine.
Tell her to make me a cambric shirt
Parsley, sage, rosemary and thyme.
Without no seams nor needle work
Then she'll be a true love of mine.